Hugo Gernsback Papers
Hugo Gernsback Papers
- Gernsback publications
  - Miscellaneous
    - Artwork, circa 1945 (Oversize 1)
      Three original paintings, probably used as cover illustrations. Two are by comic book artist Alex Schomburg and date from the mid to late 1940s; one of these features remote-controlled tanks, the other depicts soldiers operating a "Gernsback television-controlled machine gun." The third is by an unidentified artist, in a more modern style, and depicts hands assembling an unidentified electronic item.
    - Forest Mims, 1990; science writer; includes biographical sketch, photographs, negatives (Box 7)
    - Hands On Electronics cover photos, 1984-1989; undated; includes slides, color transparencies; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Historic Gernsback covers, All About Television, Science and Invention, Television News, Wonder Stories; all black-and-white reproductions, no originals (Oversize 3)
    - Historic Gernsback covers, Amazing Stories, Modern Electrics, etc.; all black-and-white reproductions, no originals; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Illustrations for unidentified book, apparently about Gernsback, photographs, captions, text, paste-ups, layout pages, etc. (Box 7)
    - Magazines, miscellaneous, 1959; 1967 (Box 7)
    - "The Magic Course" cover layout, likely for a book by Byron Wels; Wels wrote for several Gernsback publications and was apparently also a practicing magician (Oversize 3)
    - Popular Electronics, Tesla coil, circa 1990-1995; material for article, including photos, layouts, text, correspondence with Bill Evans (Box 7)
    - Popular Electronics, miscellaneous, layouts, photos, etc. (Box 7)
    - Popular Electronics, miscellaneous, circa 1990-1995; cover layouts, cover photos, etc. (Oversize 3)
    - Special Projects (SP) logos, also includes some for "Hands On Electronics" (Box 7)
    - Unidentified layouts, photos, etc. (Box 7)
- Memorabilia
  - Amazing Science Fiction Stories, vol. 34 no. 9, Sep 1960; contains profile of Gernsback, "Mr. Science Fiction" (Box 9)
  - ARKANDE[?] awards, 1957; photocopies of certificates, in German, of what appear to be personal "Hugos" given by Gernsback; recipients are Clark Darlton (Walter Ernsting) and Erich Pabel Verlag (Box 38)
  - Australian Science Fiction Convention, 3rd, 1954; proceedings, published by Futurian Society of Sydney (Box 9)
  - Awards
    - "Budding Electrician" certificate, Carmelite Convent, Luxembourg, 1890; for installing an "electrical bell system, gratis" (Box 9)
    - "Father of Magazine Science Fiction," Science Fiction Fandom, 1960; photographs of special Hugo given to Gernsback at WorldCon (Box 9)
    - First Fandom Award, See Moskowitz, Sam.
    - Helios Foundation, 1954; for "pionnier de l'education sexuelle"; photographs of award (Box 9)
    - Helios Foundation, 1953-1954; issues of their publication Lumiere & Liberte (Box 38)
    - Honorary Membership, Veteran Wireless Operators Association, 1945; VWOA Year Book, with several pages on Gernsback (Box 9)
    - Member of Honour, L'Union internationale de la presse radiotechnique et électronique, 1966 (Oversize 3)
    - Marconi Memorial Wireless Pioneers Medal, Veteran Wireless Operators Association, 1950; VWOA Year Book, with page on Gernsback (Box 9)
    - Ordre Grand Ducal de la Couronne de Chêne [Order of the Oak Crown], Grand Duchy of Luxembourg, 1954; photoreproductions of certificate, press releases, etc. (Box 9)
    - Radio Industry trophy and testimonial, 1953; includes photographs, program, and congratulatory letters from many significant individuals (e.g. David Sarnoff); 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Scroll, student engineers at New York University, 1950; program for event at which scroll was presented (Box 9)
    - Scroll, student engineers at New York University, 1950; original scroll (matted but badly deteriorated) and reproductions; 2 folders (Oversize 3)
    - Testimonial Dinner, United Jewish Appeal Electronic Distributors Division, 1953; program, news release, photographs of certificate (Box 9)
    - UNIVAC, 1964 (Oversize 3)
  - Biographical sketches, by Gernsback and others, including one item in Spanish (Box 9)
  - Blick in die zukunft [Look into the future], Science Fiction Club Deutschland, Sep/Oct 1958 (Box 9)
  - Clippings
    These include clippings from newspapers, Sunday inserts (e.g. American Weekly), magazines, trade journals, etc. Many of the newspaper clippings are essentially duplicates, being copies of syndicated columns that appeared in various newspapers across the country. The majority are American publications, but there are a few items from outside the United States.
    - About Gernsback, 1932; 1934,; 1943-1953; 5 folders (Box 9)
    - About Gernsback, 1954-1960; 12 folders (Box 10)
    - About Gernsback, 1960-1967; 1970-1971,; 1990; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - About Gernsback, undated; includes articles in Spanish, Swedish, French, and Italian, some with typed translations; typescript of article by Helen V. Tooker with corrections, evidently for a Puerto Rican publication (Box 11)
    - About Gernsback, 1957-1958; 1963,; undated; includes reprint of newspaper[?] article on flying saucers, with Gernsback illustration and reference; feature story on Gernsback in Spanish edition of LIFE from 26 Jul 1963; one-panel color comic illustrating "pop-out TV" from unidentified newspaper (Oversize 1)
    - About Sidney Gernsback (brother), 1953 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965; photoreproduction of New York Times headline and photo about Russian spacewalk (Oversize 1)
  - Engineering Society of Detroit, 19th annual meeting, 1955 (Box 11)
  - Fantasy Times [fanzine], 1955-1956; two issues that mention Gernsback (Box 11)
  - Future Science Fiction, Apr 1959; includes editorial "Yesterday's World of Tomorrow" that discusses Gernsback and his novel Ralph 124C 41+ (Box 11)
  - Golden Atom [fanzine], 1955; signed and inscribed to Gernsback by editor Larry Farsace (Box 11)
  - "Great Prophet in Christmas Cards", large-scale reprint of article about Gernsback by Clark Kinnaird, from King Features Syndicate; possibly a sales/marketing item targeted at local newspapers (Oversize 1)
  - Guest book, "WRNY, the radio news magazine station", 1927-1928 (Box 11)
  - Henry Ford Museum, 1957; flier and reservation form for appearance by Gernsback (Box 11)
    See also Writings: Speeches: Fifty years hence, Henry Ford Museum.
  - "Hugo Gernsback: Father of science fiction" by Sam Moskowitz, 1959; published by Criterion Linotype as "a birthday card to Hugo Gernsback" (Box 11)
  - Kablegram No. 1, 1958; cover story, "Hugo Gernsback: 50 years as a publishing pioneer" (Box 11)
  - Obituaries, Gernsback, 1967 (Box 11)
  - The Original Science Fiction Stories, Jan 1958; contains poem by Isaac Asimov, criticizing "New Wave" science fiction and referencing Gernsback (Box 11)
  - Photographs
    - Gernsback, Gernsback as child, young man; at home, at work, at various events; Gernsback family home in Luxembourg; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Gernsback, Gernsback as young man; at work (Oversize 3)
    - Gernsback, formal portrait (Oversize 1)
    - Gernsback and related, series of approximately 60 photographs, numbered and with detailed captions, covering Gernsback's life and career; many are stamped "Return to Harvey Gernsback" or "H. GERNSBACK"; some are stamped "USED IN LIFE JUL 26 1963" referring to a story on pp. 62-68 of that issue, entitled "Barnum of the Space Age: Amazing Hugo Gernsback and his space age scientific prophecies" (Oversize 4, 5)
      See also Clippings: About Gernsback in Oversize 1 above.
    - Electro Importing Company, 1910-1911; "the first and original radio store in the world"; appear to be those used in advertising broadside, above (Oversize 6)
  - Pins, lapel pins for Radio League, Short Wave League (Box 11)
  - "Plan de Situation des terrains Gernsbacher M. & C.ie", undated; diagram of area of Luxembourg near the Place Adolphe and Boulevard de la Haute-Petrusse (Oversize 1)
  - Radio Club of America Diamond Jubilee Year Book, 1984; bound volume (Box 12)
  - Radio Club of America Fellowship award, 1975; large plaque, M. Harvey Gernsback (Oversize 8)
  - Radio station license KE2XSX, 1956; photoreproductions of license to operate experimental station at Kingsbridge Armory in New York City, in connection with demonstration of early radio equipment for annual meeting of Institute of Radio Engineers (Oversize 1)
  - Radio-Electronics 75th Anniversary, 1983; includes commemorative reprint of vol. 1, no. 1 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1935; 1951,; 1967; mostly clippings, some newsletters and other printed items; 1 volume (Oversize 7)
  - Society of Wireless Pioneers Year Book, 1973 (Box 12)
  - "Tell Tale Tail Lamp" invention, 1907; 1909; sketch, notarized description (Box 12)
  - Trieste film festival catalog, 1963; exhibit catalog from first "Festival internazionale del film di fantascienza" (Box 12)
  - Utopia Sonderband, no. 1, 1955; dedicated to Gernsback, signed by Walter Ernsting (Box 12)
  - Utopia Sonderband, no. 2, [1955?]; contains article by Walter Ernsting, "Hugo Gernsback, der Vater der Science Fiction" and reproduction of signed/inscribed photograph on inside cover (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous artifact, homemade microphone, or detector of some sort? (Oversize 13)
    (1) Hollow brass tube mounted on stand, swivels up and down, similar to a table microphone stand; and (2) clear acrylic rod with large circular metal piece on the end. The two pieces are connected by two wires. One end of each wire is affixed to the brass tube. The other end of one is soldered to the circular metal piece; the other wire ends in a small alligator clip.
  - Miscellaneous artifacts, 18 items (Oversize 14)
    (A) Discs (4) of unidentified material, approximately 3" in diameter
    (B) Discs (2) of similar unidentified material, broken
    (C) Vacuum tubes (2) with different interior structures; one on 2-prong base, the other with cloth-wrapped wires protruding
    (D) Metal disc with 2 strips of conductive tape [?]
    (E) Metal item, 4" long, label reads "Amperex Radiation counter GC151N"
    (F) Miscellaneous small loose items (6)
    (G) Disc of some sort of translucent plastic
    (H) Wax cylinder in wooden case labeled ELECTRO IMPORTING Co. NEW YORK
  - Miscellaneous artifacts, 5 items (Oversize 15)
    (A) Discs (2) of similar unidentified material, approximately 8" in diameter
    (B) Homemade circuit board
    (C) Broken piece of disc similar to item A
    (D) Box labeled "ELECTRET COMPOUND A Mfg. by Geo. A. Miel, Co. Inc. Box 263 Lyndhurst, New Jersey," containing two blocks of the material
- Subject files
  The vast majority of material in this series consists of photographs, either original or reproductions. Many have detailed typed captions. There are also drawings, sketches, color positives and negatives, a few slides, and scattered pieces of product literature, correspondence, and clippings. Titles in this series are those given on the original folders; in the case of unlabelled folders or loose material, titles supplied during processing are indicated by square brackets [ ].
  - Amplifiers (Box 12)
  - Ancient TVs and radios, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - [Animals], mostly cats (Box 12)
  - Antennas (Box 12)
  - Antennas, radio (Box 12)
  - Antennas, transmitting, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Antennas, transmitting (Box 38)
  - Antennas, TV (Box 13)
  - Atoms (Box 13)
  - Audio, general (Box 13)
  - Auto electronics, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Automation (Box 13)
  - Batteries, dry and storage (Box 13)
  - Betatron (Box 13)
  - Biographies, brief bios of significant individuals, e.g. John Ambrose Fleming, David Sarnoff, etc. (Box 13)
  - Biological [empty folder] (Box 13)
  - Boating radio (Box 13)
  - Broadcasting (Box 13)
  - Burglar alarms (Box 13)
  - Capacitors (Box 13)
  - Carborundum (Box 13)
  - Careers (Box 13)
  - Careers (Box 14)
  - [Cars], includes slides (Box 14)
  - CDs (Box 14)
  - Censorship, 1941-1943; 1946; clippings, correspondence, etc; includes request from US military to classify photographs of Klystron (specialized linear-beam vacuum tube) (Box 14)
  - Charts (Box 14)
  - Chemicals (Box 14)
  - Citizens band [CB] radio, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - [Clocks] (Box 14)
  - Communications [empty folder] (Box 14)
  - Components (Box 14)
  - Computing devices (Box 14)
  - Controls, elect. precision (Box 14)
  - CRT tubes [cathode-ray tubes] (Box 14)
    See also Tubes, C-R.
  - Crystals (Box 14)
  - de Forest [Lee], photographs (Box 14)
  - de Forest [Lee], photographs, clippings, correspondence; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Depth sounders (Box 15)
  - Digital instruments (Box 15)
  - Dolby (Box 15)
  - Electrets (Box 15)
  - Electron microscope (Box 15)
  - Electronic ignition (Box 15)
  - Facsimile [fax machines] (Box 15)
  - Fiber optics (Box 15)
  - Fuel cells (Box 15)
  - Future transportation (Box 15)
  - [Games, computer] (Box 15)
  - Geiger counters (Box 15)
  - Gizmos (Box 15)
  - Gould [Leslie] (Box 15)
  - Halley's Comet (Box 15)
  - Historical photos, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - History of TV, includes corporate publications from RCA; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - IC digital clock, includes correspondence with Larry Steckler (Box 16)
  - Integrated circuits (Box 16)
  - Jules Verne medal (Box 16)
  - Lasers (Box 16)
  - Light beam transmission (Box 16)
  - Logic lab (Box 16)
  - LTD Motor Services, 1952-1955; relates to car radios (Box 16)
  - Manipulators (Box 16)
  - MATV [Master Antenna] systems, includes product literature from various companies including RCA and Winegard; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - MATV [Master Antenna] systems, includes product literature from various companies including RCA and Winegard; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Medical electronics (Box 17)
  - Metal detectors and mine locators (Box 17)
  - Microphones (Box 17)
  - Microwave cooking (Box 17)
  - Microwave equipment (Box 17)
  - Mobile radio (Box 17)
  - Moon photos (Box 17)
  - Moon radio (Box 17)
  - Music (Box 17)
  - Old equipment, drawings and line art only, no photographs (Box 17)
  - Oscilloscopes (Box 17)
  - Oscilloscopes (Box 38)
  - Patents [Gernsback] (Box 17)
    - Hydraulic fishery, 1955 (Box 17)
    - Physiophone/Osophone, 1912; [1924?] (Box 17)
    - Tandem bottle closure (Box 17)
  - Patents [others], mostly various bottle tops, presumably research for his own patent above (Box 17)
  - Philharmonic Hall (Box 17)
  - Photography (Box 17)
  - Portraits, A-B, various individuals significant in the radio, television, and electronics industries (Box 17)
  - Portraits, C-Z, unidentified, and groups, various individuals significant in the radio, television, and electronics industries; 6 folders (Box 18)
  - Printed circuits (Box 18)
  - Proximity fuses (Box 18)
  - Public address systems (Box 18)
  - Radar ovens (Box 18)
  - Radar, LORAN [long range navigation] (Box 18)
  - Radar, LORAN [long range navigation] (Box 38)
  - Radio, car (Box 18)
    See also LTD Motor Services, above.
  - Radio history, clippings (Box 18)
  - Radio history, clippings; 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Radio history, photographs; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Radio meteorology (Box 19)
  - Radio parts and accessories, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Radio receivers, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Radio repair shops (Box 20)
  - Radio schools (Box 20)
  - Readouts (Box 20)
  - Recorders, tape or wire, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - [Recording] (Box 20)
  - Recording studio (Box 20)
  - Rectifiers (Box 20)
  - Relays (Box 20)
  - Remote control rockets (Box 20)
  - Resistors (Box 20)
  - Satellites (Box 20)
  - SATV [satellite television] (Box 20)
  - Service shops (Box 20)
  - Signal Corps (Box 20)
  - Snooperscope (Box 20)
  - Sound (Box 20)
  - Speakers, 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Sputnik I (Box 20)
  - Stereo (Box 21)
  - Technicians and tech. assoc. (Box 21)
  - Telegraphy (Box 21)
  - Telemetering and remote control (Box 21)
  - Telephones (Box 21)
  - [Television], See folders starting with "TV" below.
  - Tesla, Nikola, photographs and clippings; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Test equipment, 5 folders (Box 21)
  - Test equipment, industrial lab (Box 21)
  - Test equipment, industrial lab (Box 22)
  - Test equipment, servicing, 5 folders (Box 22)
  - Test instruments, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Thermo-electricity (Box 22)
  - Tools, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Toys (Box 22)
  - Transistors (Box 22)
  - Transmitter equipment, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Transmitters, broadcast AM/FM (Box 23)
  - Tubes (Box 23)
  - Tubes, C-R, 2 folders (Box 23)
    See also CRT tubes [cathode-ray tubes].
  - Tubes, industrial (Box 23)
  - Tubes, receiving, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Tubes, special (Box 23)
  - Tubes, transmitting, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Tuners (Box 24)
  - Turntables (Box 24)
  - [TV cameras] (Box 24)
  - TV color history, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - TV components, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - TV GE [General Electric] (Box 24)
  - TV industrial (Box 24)
  - TV patterns and call letters (Box 24)
  - TV raster troubles, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - TV receiver boosters (Box 24)
  - TV scope patterns, 3 folders (Box 25)
  - TV sets (Box 25)
  - TV test patterns (Box 25)
  - TV tubes (Box 25)
  - Ultrasonics (Box 25)
  - VHF (Box 25)
  - Video, ancient (Box 25)
  - Video cassette recorders [VCRs], includes product information from manufacturers; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Video cassette recorders [VCRs], includes product information from manufacturers (Box 38)
  - Video disc systems, includes product information from manufacturers; 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Video disc systems, includes product information from manufacturers (Box 38)
  - Video tape recorders (Box 26)
  - Visie-Talkie, one of Gernsbacks "April Fool" items (Box 26)
  - Voice of America (Box 26)
  - Wamoscope [WAve-MOdulated oscilloSCOPE] (Box 26)
  - Wave form photos, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - X-ray (Box 26)
  - [Unidentified photos, negatives, etc.], 3 folders (Box 26)
- Writings
  - List of Gernsback publications, spanning 1908-1953, includes "one-shots" (Box 27)
  - Articles
    - Amazing Stories editorials, 1926-1929; first folder has list of dates/titles; formats include originals, reproductions, and photocopies; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Amazing Stories guest editorial, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Atom-electronics, 1954; includes clippings from publication in Turkish and German papers (Box 27)
    - Atomelectronics in 1980, 1955; includes reprint of editorial along with clipping of publication in Radio Times of India (Box 27)
    - Atomic energy and radio, in Radio-Craft, Oct 1945 (Box 27)
    - Atomic gun in 1915, in Radio-Electronics, 1945; reprint of 1915 editorial with added commentary (Box 27)
    - The automobile of the future, in Motor Critic vol. IV No. 2, 1955; related to Gernsback's speech to the Engineering Society of Detroit (Box 27)
    - Berlin to New York in less than one hour, in Everyday Science and Mechanics, Nov 1931 (Box 27)
    - Call the teledoctor, in The American Weekly, 6 Mar 1955 (Box 27)
    - Can we radio the moon?, 1946; reprint of 1927 editorial with added commentary (Box 27)
    - Crystron lapel radio (writing as Mohammed Fips), in Radio-Craft, Apr 1947 (Box 27)
    - Electric gyro-cruiser, in Electrical Experimenter, Feb 1916 (Box 27)
    - Electrical Experimenter editorials, 1915-1920; first folder has list of dates/titles; formats include originals, reproductions, and photocopies; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Electricity and gold fishes, in Electrical Experimenter, Dec 1917 (Box 27)
    - Electro-magnetic brakes for aeroplanes, in Electrical Experimenter, Jun 1918 (Box 27)
    - Electrocuting whales, in Practical Electrics, Jul 1924 (Box 27)
    - Electronic alarms, in Radio Times of India, Dec 1955 (Box 27)
    - The electronic duel, in Esquire, May 1955 (Box 27)
    - Electronic test paper, 1963; typescript with corrections (Box 27)
    - Everyday Science and Mechanics editorials, 1930-1936; first folder has list of dates/titles; formats include originals, reproductions, and photocopies; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - La exploracion de Marte, in Más Allá (Argentina) vol. 2 no. 15, Aug 1954; full issue and copies of cover art (Box 27)
    - Express super-liner, in Everyday Science and Mechanics, Oct 1933 (Box 27)
    - Extra service, in Radioman, Feb 1954 (Box 27)
    - The flame tank, in Everyday Science and Mechanics, Jan 1936 (Box 27)
    - Forty years of home radio, in Radio-Craft, Jan 1945 (Box 27)
    - Fifty years of home radio, in Radio-Electronics, Mar 1956; reprint (Box 27)
    - Have you a white elephant on your hands? In Swap & Sell, Mar 1938 (Box 27)
    - Hearing through the teeth, in Science and Invention, Nov 1923 (Box 27)
    - How to feed 10 billion people, May 1953; clippings from various US newspapers (Box 27)
    - How long do books last?, typescript (Box 27)
    - The hypnotone, in Everyday Science and Mechanics, Apr 1934 (Box 27)
    - Inventions wanted, [1960?]; typescript drafts; also includes booklet with same title from National Inventors Council (Box 27)
    - Magnesium paper substitute, [1955]; typescript; rejection note from Coronet magazine (Box 27)
    - Magnesium paper substitute, mounted illustrations for article (Oversize 1)
    - The magnetic storm, in Electrical Experimenter, Aug 1918 (Box 28)
    - Making the most of the moon, in American Weekly, Dec 1952 (Box 28)
    - Man vs moon, Jun 1961; handwritten draft (Box 28)
    - Miracle from the sea, in Family Weekly, 11 Sep 1960; handwritten draft; published clipping (Box 28)
    - Monstrous machines of the next war, in Everyday Mechanics, Oct 1934 (Box 28)
    - New Ideas editorials, Nov 1937; vol. 1 no. 1 only (Box 28)
    - Nikola Tesla, father of wireless, in Radio-Craft, Feb 1943 (Box 28)
    - The not-so-mighty human race, 1954 (Box 28)
    - Official Martian report, AD 2222, typescript (Box 28)
    - One hundred years hence, in Everyday Science and Mechanics, Sep 1932 (Box 28)
    - Our airships cannot be moored to skyscrapers, in Everyday Science and Mechanics, May 1932 (Box 28)
    - Our feeble senses, in Science Digest, Apr 1954 (Box 28)
    - The Physiophone, in Electrical Experimenter, Apr 1920 (Box 28)
    - Probleme der Farben-TV [Problems of color tv], in Radio Service, 1954 (Box 28)
    - PsItTaFaCtS, 1962; handwritten draft, noted as "for Journal of the Institute of Twenty-First Century Studies" (Box 28)
    - The Radio League of America, in Electrical Experimenter, Dec 1915; reprint (Box 28)
    - Radio News editorials, 1919-1929; first folder has list of dates/titles; formats include originals, reproductions, and photocopies; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Radio & Television editorials, 1940-1941; first folder has list of dates/titles; formats include originals, reproductions, and photocopies; 2 folders (Box 28)
      See Writings by others: Radio & Television editorials for 1939 items.
    - The radio-controlled television plane, in The Experimenter, Nov 1924 (Box 28)
    - Radio-Craft editorials, 1929-1942; first folder has list of dates/titles; formats include originals, reproductions, and photocopies; 6 folders (Box 28)
    - Radio-Craft editorials, 1943-1948; formats include originals, reproductions, and photocopies; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Radio-Electronics $1400 prize contest, 1964?; handwritten draft (Box 29)
    - Radio-Electronics April Fool articles, 1952; 1954-1955,; 1957-1958,; 1960-1965,; undated; handwritten drafts, clippings of published versions; some also have related clippings, photographs, etc.; 12 folders (Box 29)
    - Radio-Electronics editorials, 1948-1956; handwritten drafts, clippings of published versions; some also have related clippings, photographs, etc.; 13 folders (Box 29)
    - Radio-Electronics editorials, 1957-1962; handwritten drafts, clippings of published versions; some also have related clippings, photographs, etc.; 16 folders (Box 30)